Good dogs don't block the way, you know.
我真的想说好狗不挡道
A new hire at our company?
咱们公司来新人了
How would I know?
我哪知道啊
I didn't get any notice.
我又没有收到通知
Do you see how tall he is?
你看他有多高啊
How could I?
我哪看得出他多高
Anyway, he looks
反正看着
tall and slim,
高高瘦瘦的
with a clean face.
脸长得干干净净的
He's my type.
是我喜欢的类型
Look at him smiling like that.
瞧他笑得那样
A man without self-respect
男人不自爱
is like rotten cabbage.
就像棵烂白菜
He's just smiling normally.
人家笑得很正常啊
Are you implying something
合着赵经理在这儿给我
about me?
指桑骂槐呢
Even rotten cabbage
这烂白菜吧
can get infested with worms,
它也有虫蛀
but what's worse
怕的是什么呢
is when the cabbage rots away
这白菜放在犄角旮旯里
in a corner, completely ignored.
发霉了都无人问津
Who's completely ignored?
谁无人问津
I'm proudly single.
我这是高傲的独身
Qi Yu?
齐郁
Xiaoning?
筱柠
How fancy!
真是你啊
Long time no see.
好久不见
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿啊
I came to...
我来是给
Qi Yu?
齐郁吗
Mr. Ji.
纪总
Hello.
你好
Turns out,
人家自己人
it's old friends reuniting.
要胜利会师了
Did the president arrive
行长昨天晚上
at the provincial office last night?
到省行了吗
Yes.
到了
President?
行长
He won't be back for a couple of days.
行长这两天回不来
He asked me to bring you some documents
让我来给您送份资料
and check in on you.
顺便慰问一下您
How's your arm?
您的胳膊还好吧
Much better,
好多了
thanks for asking.
谢谢老师的关心
All right,
行
please come to the office.
办公室请吧
President?
行长
What's going on?
什么情况啊
I'm his new driver.
我是行长新招的司机
Heading in now.
进去了啊
Okay, okay.
好 好
Jing,
姐
I brought back the documents you needed.
你要的资料取回来了
You can leave.
回去吧
Okay.
好
Xiaoning,
筱柠
so you work here too?
原来你也在这儿办公啊
I've been here for a while.
我来这有一段时间了
When did you come back,
你 什么时候回来的呀
and why did you decide to return?
怎么想着回来了呢
For the reason you're thinking.
就是你想得那原因
You...
你
you...
你这个人吧
I know what you wanna say,
我知道你想说什么
but I still
但我还是想
wanna give it another try.
为自己再争取一次
So, have you
那你想好
thought about what to do next?
接下来该怎么办了吗
So he's the
搞了半天
president's driver?
原来是行长的司机啊
Yes, yes.
是 是 是
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
You two...
你们俩
are you in that kind of relationship?
原来你们是那种关系
What kind of relationship?
哪种关系
Qi Yu come here because of you?
小齐来应聘是为了你
No.
不是
No, no, no,
不 不 不
you misunderstood, Mr. Zhao.
你误会了赵经理
Then isn't this
那你们这不就
an office romance?
成办公室恋情了吗
Dating on company time,
你说公费谈恋爱
how bold.
好大的胆子啊
It's thrilling
主打就是一个惊险
and romantic.
浪漫
No,
不
what thrill, what romance?
什么惊喜浪漫
I think he's funny.
我觉得他好好玩啊
Yeah,
对呀
why is that?
这是为啥呀
Last time.
上次
So bad.
太坏了这也
Send this to me, send it to me.
这个你发给我 发给我
Okay.
我发给你
I'll send it to you.
我发给你啊
Everyone,
各位
it's been an hour since work started,
上班已经一个小时了
and you've been away for so long?
集体离开工位这么久
What?
怎么
Is there something
是有什么
urgent work-related?
工作上的要紧事吗
I was in a rush this morning and
早晨出门太着急了
didn't have time to use the bathroom,
没来得及上厕所
so I had to go.
就去蹲了会儿
A group bathroom break?
集体组团上厕所
For an hour?
还是一个小时
Looks like you drank a lot yesterday.
看来昨天没少喝啊
Xu Li,
许力
your client decided to come over
刚刚你的客户临时决定
unexpectedly,
过来找你
but he couldn't find you,
但他没找到你
so I handled it.
我替你接待了
This shouldn't
下次不允许
happen again.
再发生这样的事情
What are you standing there for?
愣着干吗呀
Hurry up and thank Mr. Ji.
还不赶紧谢谢纪总啊
Thank you...
那个谢
Mr. Ji...
谢谢纪
Also, Li Xiang, this is
另外李想
your third time being late this week.
这是你本周第三次迟到
According to Dairui's regulations,
按照代瑞的规定
you'll lose half a month's bonus.
要扣你半个月的绩效
Three strikes, and next time
事不过三如果再有下次
you'll either be transferred
要么转岗
or terminated.
要么离职
What?
这话说得
You can't just terminate me.
我签的是正式合同
I have a formal contract.
凭什么离职
As an employee of this company,
凭你是这个单位的员工
you must follow
就得遵守
its rules and regulations.
这个单位的规章制度
Mr. Ji,
纪总
what do you mean by this?
你到底什么意思啊
Li Xiang lives far away,
李想家住得远
and sometimes the elevator
有时候电梯
delays his punch-in
慢个一两分钟
by a minute or two.
耽误了打卡
It's not intentional.
也不是有意的
Mr. Ji, you mentioned rules,
纪总您说规定
so let's follow them.
那我们就按规定来
Now it's work time.
现在规定是工作时间了
Everyone,
大家
get back to work!
都干起来
Fanggang,
赵哥
good thing you were here today,
幸亏有你
otherwise this
要不然今天这事
could have gotten out of hand.
还不知道要闹多大
Fanggang, if not for giving you face...
赵哥我不是给你面子
All right, all right.
好了 好了
Listen to me,
听哥一句劝
let's all keep
咱们最近啊
a low profile for a while.
都低调一点
We don't want
别又被这个
the Compliance Dept
合规部下来的主
catching us on anything.
抓住了小辫儿
Get back to work.
去工作吧
Calm down.
消消气啊
It's fine.
没事
Grab your medical kit
拿上你的医疗包
and come to the rooftop.
来天台一趟
Why,
怎么
found a new meeting spot?
找到了新的接头地点
The stairwell isn't safe anymore.
楼梯间已经不安全了
From now on,
以后在公司
if we need to talk,
有什么事的话
we'll do it on the rooftop.
就来天台上说
Why are you staring at me?
你看着我干什么
The stairwell isn't safe anymore?
楼梯间不安全了
What do you mean?
什么意思呀
You know about Qi Yu?
齐郁的事你知道了
Know what,
知道什么
that you and Qi Yu
知道你跟齐郁
were seen talking in the stairwell
在楼梯间聊天
by Zhao Fanggang and the others,
被赵方刚他们看到了
and they said
然后还说
he's your suitor
他是你的追求者
or ex-boyfriend?
还是前男友啊
Don't listen to their nonsense.
你别听他瞎说
What suitor, what ex-boyfriend?
什么追求者前男友啊
We have nothing to do with each other.
我们俩什么关系都没有
It's already enough of a headache
咱俩在一个公司
working in the same company as you.
已经够让我头疼了
Do you think I'm crazy enough
我脑子是不是有病啊
to bring an ex-boyfriend here?
我再找个前男友来公司
I know.
我知道
What do you know?
你又知道什么
You've only had one relationship, right?
你不是只有一段感情吗
Given your character,
以你的性格
it's impossible for you
在一段感情里
to have two exes at the same time
不可能同时
in one relationship.
出现两个前任
Ouch.
疼
Serves you right.
活该
Do you enjoy
你是不是很享受
having control
这种感觉
over others?
就是拿捏别人的感觉
You know
你明明知道
Qi Yu and I
我跟齐郁
have nothing to do with each other,
什么关系都没有
yet you still tease me.
你还非要逗我
You knew
明知道赵经理
where Mr. Zhao went,
他去哪儿了
but you still asked,
还非要去问
to make an example of him.
然后杀鸡儆猴
So you think
所以你觉得
I'm just scaring them?
我是在吓唬他们
Shouldn't Li Xiang and the others
难道李想他们
be punished?
不应该被罚吗
They should be punished,
该罚是该罚
but
但是
you should also give them some face.
也要给人家留点面子吧
Otherwise,
要不然你这样
you'll lose their support.
会失去人心的
All thanks to Mr. Zhao.
多亏了赵经理帮你解围
Is this good enough?
这样就可以了吧
Regarding Qi Yu, although
齐郁的事情呢
we have nothing to do with each other,
虽然我们俩没什么关系
since
但是
we work at the same bank,
毕竟在一个银行工作
we should hide
咱们还是要在他面前
our relationship
隐藏好我们的身份
from him.
不要让他发现什么
You two are classmates?
你们是同学
Not just classmates,
不止同学
he's my
他是我
best friend's
最好的闺蜜的
ex-boyfriend.
前男友
I don't even know
我都不知道
what will happen
他们俩见面
if they meet.
会发生什么事儿呢
Haven't been here in a few days,
几天没见
why is it so busy here?
怎么这么红火啊
Suddenly so many people,
突然这么多人
are they
这不会是
hired to line up?
雇来排队的托儿吧
You don't know?
你不知道吗
Yesterday this store
昨天这家店
started a group-buy promotion
在短视频平台上
on the short video platform.
上了团购
Buy two, get one free
网红芝士蛋糕
on their famous cheesecake.
买二送一呢
Today is the first day.
今天第一天
So if I don't use the group-buy,
那如果不用团购
I don't have to line up?
是不是就不用排队了
Big spender, huh?
财大气粗啊
Everyone's lining up here.
大家都在这儿排队呢
You think you can cut the line?
你还想插队不成
Nothing is impossible
世上无难事
if you're willing to give up.
只要肯放弃
I won't eat here.
不吃这家了
You've been hungry all day.
饿了一天了
Just eat.
快吃吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
It was my fault before.
之前都是我不对
My parents
我爸妈
want me to move back home,
想让我回老家发展
and I didn't wanna disappoint them.
我不想他们失望
I neglected your feelings,
疏忽你的感受
I'm really sorry.
真对不起
You're not wrong.
你没错
Life has more than
人生能选择的路
one path to choose from.
本来就不只有一条
You made your choice.
你做出了自己的选择
There's nothing wrong with that.
有什么好错的
I was wrong.
我有错
I thought I could
我以为我当时的我
balance our relationship...
能平衡好咱们之间的
Weiyi,
惟依
I found a job
我在你工作的楼里
in your building.
也找了份工作
It's stable,
挺稳定的
and I won't be away anymore.
不会再跟你异地了
I'll be here whenever
以后只要你需要我
you need me.
我一直在
No wonder Xiaoning called me.
怪不得筱柠和我打电话
You guys met at work?
你们在公司遇到了
I joined Dairui
我入职代瑞
to be the president's driver.
给行长开车
I can tell you everything
所有你想了解的
you wanna know.
我都可以跟你讲
But you've been hungry all day.
但你饿了一天了
Want to eat something first?
要不要先吃点东西
I got you your favorite...
我给你买的最爱吃的
How did you know
你怎么知道
I've been hungry all day?
我饿了一天了
Xiaoning told me
我听筱柠说
you took a leave today to rest at home.
你今天请假在家休息
You always forget
你睡觉的时候
to eat and keep irregular hours
总是顾不上吃饭
when you sleep,
作息不规律
how could I not know?
我能不知道吗
You still know me so well.
你还是那么了解我
Then you should know
那你就该知道
I'm not one
我不是一个
to take back an ex.
吃回头草的人
Qi Yu,
齐郁
you're already history to me.
你在我这儿已经翻篇了
I admit,
我承认
I was waiting for you to regret
之前我是在等你后悔
and come back.
等你回头
But now,
但是现在
that means
那些对我
nothing to me.
都没什么意义了
Hey man,
大哥
you on duty today?
今儿你值班呢
Yeah, yeah.
对 对 对
Here, have a cigarette.
来 抽根烟
No, I can't.
不行 不行 不行
Take it, just take it.
拿着 拿着
Don't be shy.
你别跟我客气
Please.
别跟我客气
Just take it.
拿着 拿着
Thanks.
谢谢啊
How's it going
最近怎么样啊
in the park lately?
在园区里边
It's been good,
最近挺好的
lots of people around.
人也挺多的
Mr. Wu's car is over there.
吴总的车就在那边
Thanks.
谢谢啊
No problem.
没事 没事
Wondering why
你是不是想问
I chatted so long with the gatekeeper
门卫是园区的
when he's just part of the park
跟里边企业没什么关系
and not related
我为什么
to the companies inside?
要跟他聊那么久
I was a bit curious.
确实有点好奇
The guardroom
传达室
is a hub for gossip.
是小道消息的聚集地
The gatekeepers
门卫呢
know every
能熟知这园区里
boss's car,
每一位老板开的什么车
their schedules,
出入时间
and even their personalities.
甚至 他们的性格
But I remember the boss here
但我记得这家老板
said
说过
they don't need loans.
不贷款啊
I get it,
我明白了
Mr. Zhao, you're thinking just because
赵经理你想的是
they don't need it now
现在不需要
doesn't mean they won't in the future.
不代表以后不需要
So you come by
没事过来晃一圈
to leave an impression,
留点印象
so when they need it,
等需要的时候
they'll think of you first.
直接就会来找你
You're good.
聪明
Marketing isn't about quick wins.
做营销不能急于求成
Even the best companies
再优质的企业
have cash flow
他也会有
issues sometimes.
资金周转不开的时候
We need to play
我们要学会放长线
the long game.
钓大鱼
Come on,
来
it's almost lunchtime.
快到饭点了
Have something to eat.
垫吧 垫吧
Thanks, Mr. Zhao.
谢谢赵经理
You're welcome.
不客气
So,
我说呢
you're shadowing me
这么迫切地跟来
to learn about the park's business
学习园区业务
for your
就是为了应付
regularization exam, right?
转正考试呗
I did sign up for
我确实利用下班时间
some online courses
报了一些
for the regularization exam after work,
转正业务的网课
but I found
但是我发现
I lack practical experience,
很多实操经验我不足
so I don't fully understand everything.
所以理解得不够到位
You're right.
你说得没错
Marketing
做营销啊
requires adaptability.
随机应变
It's not just about book knowledge;
但光记纸上没用
you have to use your head.
得靠这儿
Mr. Zhao,
赵经理
I know
其实我知道
it's not your duty to teach me,
您没这个义务教我
but you've been so patient
但是你还那么耐心
and taught me so much.
跟我讲了这么多
I've learned a lot from
跟您跑了半天园区
shadowing you in the park.
实打实地学了不少东西
Thank you, Mr. Zhao.
谢谢赵经理
You're welcome.
不客气 来
When I first joined Dairui,
我刚入行代瑞的时候
a senior guided me
也是前辈带着我
and taught me hands-on.
手把手地教我
Now that I'm the senior,
我现在成前辈了
I have to pass on
那不得传承一下
such good traditions.
咱们代瑞的优良传统吗
If you really wanna thank me,
要是你真想感谢我
stop calling me Mr. Zhao.
以后就别叫我赵经理了
It sounds too formal.
怪生疏的
Just call me
以后就叫
Fanggang.
小赵哥
By the way,
那个
is that driver your boyfriend?
行长司机是你男朋友吧
No.
不是
Don't lie.
你别瞒了
I think you're
我觉得你俩
a good match.
还是挺般配的
But
但是啊
keep it low-key.
还是得低调
It still counts as an office romance.
也算是办公室恋情吧
He's really not!
他真不是我男朋友
Listen,
你听我说
it's better not to admit it,
不承认也好
or you'll get caught
免得被那位逮到
and made an example of.
再把你当个典型处理了
If you're late,
迟个到
you would lose half a month's bonus.
罚半个月绩效
If you're exposed,
这要是被他发现
he would
办公室恋情
make you... pay back
那不得罚你
the company money,
倒赔公司钱
or worse,
十有八九
fire you on the spot.
直接把你给开了
You mean...
那位是
Mr. Ji?
纪总
I don't think he's that kind of person.
我觉得他不是那样的人
Do you know what kinda person he is?
他是什么样的人你知道
Are you his partner
你是他对象
or something?
还是他什么人
Silly girl,
傻妹妹
you don't understand the workplace.
你太不懂职场了
Let's get going.
出发了
Here,
给
the coffee you've been craving.
你心心念念我泡的咖啡
Give it a try.
尝尝
Does it suit your taste?
合你口味吗
I took your trainee
今天上午我带你徒弟
around the park this morning.
跑了一圈园区
She's got a good sense for things.
挺有悟性的
This trip around the park
这一趟园区跑下来
might actually help me
我这一个月
meet my target
新增一客户的任务
of one new client this month.
可算是有点着落了
Have you heard?
你听说了吗
The higher-ups have started
上头已经开始走流程
investigating the dating loan issue.
彻查相亲贷的事情了
I think
这回呀
I've done a good job this time.
我也算是立功了吧
Shouldn't the bank
咱行
give me some recognition?
不得给我发个小红花
What good job?
你立什么功
I submitted the key evidence
这核心证据是我提交的
that exposed
直接拆穿了
Qianliyuan's true nature.
千里缘的真正面目
They have no way to deny it.
我让他们无从狡辩
Those
就你那几张
blank contracts
空白的
without even a seal,
连章都没有盖的合同
you call that evidence?
你告诉我是证据
Are you kidding me?
你跟姐玩呢
Looks like you're not convinced.
看来你不服气
Your recordings
要说你那几个录音
aren't that convincing either.
才没有说服力吧
They just
人家直接把
fired the employee who attended to you,
接待你的员工
saying the person
一开说
doesn't exist in the company.
公司压根没有这个人
What can you do?
你能怎么办
But you did contribute,
不过多少你也出了力
so I'll put in a good word for you.
我会帮你美言几句的
Don't forget to drink the coffee.
咖啡记得喝
Xiaoning,
小涂
don't worry,
你放心吧
I'll also say good things
回头纪总那边
to Mr. Ji for you.
我也会帮你说好话的
Hey, that's my trainee.
我的徒弟用你说好话吗
I'm talking about the
我在说
investigation of the dating loan issue.
彻查相亲贷的事情
Even though I submitted
虽然呢核心证据
the key evidence...
是我提交的
Jing.
静姐
Go ahead.
快去
Okay.
好
Sorry, Fanggang.
不好意思啊小赵哥
Even though I
虽然核心证据
submitted the key evidence,
是我提交的
you were involved too.
但毕竟你也参与了
When Mr. Ji asks,
回头纪总问起来
I'll highlight
我会着重渲染一下
your contribution.
你的作用
Unlocked.
已开锁
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome back.
回来了
Your wound isn't healed yet,
怎么伤还没好
and you're already eager to cook?
就迫不及待地做饭呀
This little wound is nothing.
这点小伤不算什么
Go wash your hands.
快洗手
Dinner is ready.
准备吃饭啊
Sweet and sour pork?
糖醋肉啊
You know how to make this?
你还会做糖醋肉呢
Just in time.
正好
Try it and see if it's to your taste.
尝尝看合不合口味
Okay.
好
How is it?
怎么样
Delicious,
好吃
very authentic.
很正宗
Did you make it
你是因为
because I like
我喜欢吃糖醋肉
sweet and sour pork?
所以才做得吗
It's a coincidence;
巧了
it just happens to be a dish you love.
正好这道菜是你爱吃的
What do you like to eat?
你喜欢吃什么呀
I'll remember it
我记一下
and return the favor next time.
之后投桃报李
Peaches are not okay for me.
我除了不能吃桃子
Then, I'm not picky.
其他不挑食
Gao?
小高
My scam issue
我被骗的问题
is sorted out.
已经解决了
If you hadn't called and reminded me
要不是你打电话提醒我
to negotiate with Qianliyuan,
抓住时机找千里缘谈判
I'd have lost my money
他们这要是一倒闭
if they went bankrupt.
我这钱就真没希望了
Anyway,
总之是
thank you so much.
真是太谢谢您了
No need to thank me.
不用谢
If you run into similar problems,
以后呢有这样的问题
feel free to ask me,
你还是可以问我的
anytime.
随时
Last time,
就是上次吗
I was too emotional
我情绪太冲动了
and hurt Mr. Ji.
伤了你们的纪总
I wanna apologize to him.
我想给纪总道个歉
Don't worry about it.
你不用放在心上没事的
Mr. Ji is
我们纪总呢
very understanding;
大人大量
he won't hold it against you.
不会生你气的
Oh,
哦对了
and Mr. Zhao
还有你们赵经理
called to comfort me
也给我打电话安慰我
and helped me with some personal issues.
还帮我解决了个人问题
Please thank him for me too.
也替我谢谢他吧
Sure,
好
I'll thank him for you.
我帮你谢谢他
Great, thank you very much.
好好好 谢谢谢谢
Bye.
拜拜
That was Gao.
是小高
He said...
小高他跟我说
He got his money back,
他说钱要回来了
and Zhao Fanggang
而且赵方刚
helped him a lot.
还帮了他很多忙
He also wanted to apologize to me.
他还想跟我道个歉
Is my phone's soundproofing that bad?
我手机隔音这么差吗
Did you
你是不是
already know this
见过他
from meeting
或者打过电话
or calling him?
这些你早就知道了
Why didn't you tell me?
你怎么不跟我说呀
I thought it'd be better for you to
我是觉得这些感谢的话
hear those words of gratitude directly,
还是你亲耳听到比较好
right?
对不对
Of course, it makes me happier.
那是肯定更开心
But
但是
not just because of his issue;
不光是因为他的事情
mainly because
主要是
our section one
我们拓展一部
has finally
这次的风波
weathered this storm.
总算过去了
Fanggang worked so hard
也不枉小赵哥那么辛苦
to resolve everything smoothly,
解决事情解决得很圆满
so now
大家以后
we don't have to work
也不用提心吊胆地
with our hearts in our throats anymore.
再工作了吗
Let's eat while it's hot.
快趁热吃饭吧
The bank has thoroughly investigated
行里已经彻底查清楚了
the Qianliyuan issue
千里缘的事情
and reviewed
也对其他
other similar
类似形式的消费贷
consumer loans.
进行了排查
Good job, everyone.
这段时间大家都辛苦了
The dating loan issue
相亲贷的问题上
was handled in a timely manner,
处理得还算及时
especially thanks to Ms. Rao,
尤其是饶经理
who played a very positive role,
起到了很积极的作用
setting an example for all of us.
值得我们大家去学习
Now, I'll announce
接下来我来宣布一下
the handling results
针对这次事情的
of this incident.
处理结果
On behalf of section one, I'm announcing
我代表拓展一部
a full department criticism
对相亲贷的经手人
of the person in charge
赵方刚 赵经理
of the dating loan,
进行全部门的
Mr. Zhao Fanggang.
通报批评
His bonus for this month
本月奖金
will be reduced by 30%,
核减百分之三十
and
另外
5 clients will be reassigned.
移交五个客户
Criticism, reassignment, and a pay cut?
通报批评移交客户扣钱
What's the meaning of this?
什么意思啊
Can you explain it to me?
能跟我解释一下吗
I've made myself clear;
我说得很清楚
no explanation is needed.
不需要解释
You know that Mr. Jiang
相亲贷这事
spearheaded the
是江总挑头弄的
dating loan issue, right?
这你是知道的吧
And you asked me
你让我去调查
to investigate it without hesitation.
我二话没说就去了
That's a fact, right?
这也是事实吧
I don't expect any commendation,
我也不求表彰我
but I don't understand
但你在大会上
why you're doing this to me
唱这么一出
in a public meeting.
我实在是想不通
I need an explanation.
只能来找你赐教了
You didn't
相亲贷
start this shebang.
虽然你不是挑头的
But you're the agent.
但你是经办人
I don't think this report
通报批评
is too much.
不算过分
Mr. Ji.
纪总
It doesn't make sense.
话不能这么说吧
I was an agent, yes.
我是经手了
But I have solved the problem.
但我解决了没有
I've cleaned up the mess.
我这问题处理了没有
I just got
我本来就是一个
involved into it.
受牵连的人
I've done far more than I should
后面做的这些
to make up for my mistakes!
总能将大功补过小过吧
Got involved?
受牵连
You're not the only one.
受牵连的可不只有你
It's the whole section.
是整个拓展一部
Fine.
好
I can see it.
我算是看明白了
You're determined
相亲贷这事
to blame me
你是打定主意
for all of this.
栽在我身上
The act on the meeting
在大会上唱这么一出
was for you to embarrass me
就是为了膈应我
and set me on fire,
让我难受
so you can let
让大家看看
the whole section to see
拓展一部
who the boss is.
到底是谁说了算
All those angry scenes
那一出出雷霆之怒
were all for this purpose, aren't they?
不也就是这个意思吗
If you have any complaints
赵方刚如果你对我
about me,
有什么不满的话
just take it up to the higher-ups.
可以直接向上级反映
How dare I?
我怎么敢对你不满呢
Today I'm just reported.
今天你能给我通报批评
Tomorrow I can be
明天你就能
fired by you.
把我扫地出门
But don't you forget.
但是你记住了
I've got
我赵方刚
a thing or two
能在拓展一部
to be in this department
待了快八年
for almost 8 years.
那自然有我的本事
We're colleagues.
咱俩以后
We have to work together.
低头不见抬头见
You'll see
这日子
what I've got.
还长着呢
Here.
来
Let's raise our glasses to Fanggang.
让我们一起为赵哥举杯
Come on!
来 来 来
Fanggang.
赵哥真的
Your patience and forgiveness
忍一时他厚颜无耻
can only lead to
退一步
his shamelessness.
蹬鼻子上脸他
I'm sorry for you.
受委屈了啊
Fanggang.
小赵哥
I'm useless.
窝囊
Xiaoning.
小涂
I'm such a wimp.
我就是太
I let him bully me as he please.
让人欺负到脑门上了
I've lost my face.
脸面全无
Sometimes,
有的时候人吧
especially at this moment...
越是这个时候
A man cannot give in
越不能躺在地上
and be a joke.
让人看笑话
I know.
我懂
I was a joke today.
今儿让你们看笑话了
No. Of course not.
没有 哥
This one
这顿
is on me.
我请
I'll order more.
我再点酒
Okay. Thanks.
好 谢谢小赵哥
Just do it!
来 来 来
Thank you.
谢谢哥
Waiter!
服务员
Sir.
您好
Do you have a group price?
有团购吗
Sorry, we don't.
抱歉没有的
But we have a discount
不过本店特惠
on cocktails.
鸡尾酒三组以上
50% for 3 rounds or more.
只要半价
It's a great deal.
很划算的
Give me 3.
我来三组
Okay.
好
Everybody!
大家伙
Today,
今儿啊
let's have some fine cocktail!
咱们喝点高级的啊
B-52!
轰炸机鸡尾酒
Three rounds!
三组
You're so nice!
赵哥大气 赵哥敞亮
Fanggang.
赵哥
Drink it up!
接着喝
Come on!
来 来 来
Okay!
我干了
Help yourselves!
你们随意
Drink straight from the bottle!
拿瓶吧 你还倒 来
Hello, mom.
喂 妈
What's up?
怎么了
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Where are you now?
你在哪儿呢
I'm out at a party with coworkers.
我在外面跟同事聚会呢
Why asking?
有事啊
It's the day
今天是
Ji's mom completed her therapy.
小纪妈妈的结疗日
Don't you go visit her in hospital?
你不去医院吗
How did you know it?
妈你是怎么知道的
She knew I've been looking forward
我们就一直联系着
to visiting her.
想看看她
So she told me it's her day
这不今天正好结疗吗
she ended her therapy.
她就告诉了我们一声
How about this?
那要不这样吧
I'll go to the hospital now.
我现在过去
See you there later.
咱们医院见
Okay.
好嘞
Okay. Bye.
好嘞 拜拜
Is that Rao Jing?
那是饶静吗
The one in red.
你看穿红衣服那个
Is that Jing?
那是静姐吗
Exactly!
是静姐
It's not the same guy
这和上次千里缘
at Qianliyuan?
门口那个不是一个人吧
Fanggang.
小赵哥
Sorry, but I gotta go.
我有事 我得先走了
I have a relative in hospital.
家里有人生病在医院
Sorry about that.
不好意思啊
I'm off now.
我先走了
Okay.
你先去吧
Bye.
拜拜 拜拜
Be careful!
路上注意安全
Take care.
注意安全啊
Jing's a good dancer.
静姐摇得可以啊
My god.
我的天哪
Here.
来 来
You just finished your work,
你上班都累一天了
and you have to come to see me.
晚上还跑来
It's okay, ma'am.
没事的阿姨
Mom.
妈
I'll handle this.
我来吧
You've got bruises.
青了
Xiaoning.
筱柠啊
Is Yuheng
昱恒
too boring for you?
是不是平常很闷哪
No.
没有
Let me tell you.
我跟你说呀
He
他啊
tends to keep everything to himself.
什么都藏在心里不说
If he pisses you off,
他要是惹你生气了
just tell him.
你就告诉他
Don't sulk.
别自己埋在心里
When a couple
夫妻啊
stops to talk,
隔了话
it'll harm their relationship.
就隔心了
There's
我们俩
nothing bad between us.
没有什么隔阂
Don't worry, mom.
妈你别多想了
You're already married,
这你们都结婚了
why doesn't Xiaoning
筱柠这手上
have a ring on her finger?
怎么也没个戒指啊
Yuheng.
昱恒啊
There's a gift box
我卧室床头柜
in the bottom drawer of my
底层的抽屉里
bedroom nightstand.
有一个礼盒
There's a pair of rings inside.
是一对 对戒
They're for you.
给你们的
I should have
本来呢
prepared a diamond ring
应该提前
for you in advance.
给你买个钻戒的
You can pick one up
你们有空
yourselves if you're free.
自己去看看
I'll pay the bill.
我报销
Actually,
其实
I've been meaning to get you a present.
妈一直想送你礼物
But
但是呢
I don't know if you like bracelets
不知道你是喜欢镯子呀
or necklaces.
还是项链
I didn't dare rush Yuheng to ask.
我又不敢催着昱恒问
No, mom.
真的不用
I don't need these.
妈我不要这些
Mom.
妈
Immunotherapy
这次
is pretty long this time.
免疫疗法时间还挺长的
How are you feeling?
您感觉怎么样啊
I'm feeling better.
好多了
I was just thinking
我还正想着
about telling you
跟你们商量
I'd like to
等过一阵
go home
我想
for a while.
就回家住住
Is that okay?
行吗
Yes.
行啊
You're welcome to come back.
回家住多好呀
Later, I'll vacate my room...
那我回头把我房间
No,
不是
our room,
我是说我们
for you,
把房间腾出来
okay?
给妈住
Okay.
好
Why did you call me out?
你叫我出来干什么
So it's about Zhao Fanggang.
所以是因为
You're unhappy
赵方刚的事情
with my decision.
让你不开心了
One month's bonus
扣他一个月的奖金
and five clients.
移交五名客户
The loss is not much of a punishment.
这个处分不算重
"Not much"?
不算重
If your leader give you such a
你的领导无缘无故
big punishment for no reason...
给你这么大的一个处分
Wait,
不是
for no reason?
什么叫无缘无故
Zhao Fanggang
是非对错
knows well
在赵方刚的心里
right from wrong.
他很清楚
But you did it
那也要讲一个
in an inappropriate way.
方式方法吧
You gave him
你什么都不说
such a big punishment
直接给一个
without a explain.
这么大的处分
It's like you're using him
就好像拿小赵哥
to intimidate us.
来给自己立威泄愤一样
Right.
行
I see.
我算是听明白了
So in your mind
所以在你心里你觉得
you feel that
我在处理
I'm not handling this
这件事情的时候
in a delicate way
没有考虑到
for him.
赵方刚的感受
Xiaoning.
筱柠
I do my job
我在开展工作的时候
with efficiency.
讲究的是效率
How can I be efficient
如果我每做一件事情
if I have to consider
都要考虑所有人的感受
everyone's feelings
所有人的情绪
and emotions in everything?
我的工作怎么开展
So you don't think
所以你觉得
you did anything wrong,
你自己没有做错
do you?
对吧
Right.
也是
You're so careful with your words.
你这么惜字如金的
We don't deserve
怎么会
any explain from you
跟我们这种小人物解释
about what's
你心里
on your mind.
到底是想什么的呢
As for what's on our mind,
我们到底怎么想的呢
you don't care at all.
对你来说也不重要
Of course I didn't mean that.
我当然不是这个意思
You can't...
你不能
I can't do what?
不能什么
Make it personal?
上纲上线
Mr. Ji.
纪总啊 纪总
I've learned my lesson today.
我今天算是明白了
I didn't know
我对你
anything about you.
根本一点都不了解
I think we're getting
我觉得我们情绪
kind of emotional.
有点激动
We better calm down now.
都先冷静 冷静
Stop arguing.
先不说了
Isn't that the couple?
那不他俩吗
Yes.
还真是啊
Why does it look like an argument?
怎么像吵架了
It is an argument.
这还真是吵架了
Why are you so nervous?
你紧张什么呀
They are still young.
那年轻人拌拌嘴
Isn't an argument normal?
那不是很正常吗
What about us now?
那咱俩怎么办呢
What do you mean?
咱俩怎么了
We made an appointment
咱跟孩子约好了
with them to take us
让孩子带着咱们
to the in-law.
去见亲家
Now they're fighting
那现在他俩
and taking
一个往东一个往西
leaves.
人都走了
It's okay.
没关系
We can go there
咱俩自己上去
ourselves.
不就得了吗
Is that proper?
那好吗
Of course it is.
这有什么好不好的呀
Besides, we've already
再说你看咱俩
prepared the gifts
东西都买了
for the in-law.
汤都煲了
Let's go now.
上去吧
Actually
亲家
we've been
其实我们
wanting to see you for a long time.
早就想来看您了
But we've heard that you're not
但是听说您
well enough to meet people,
身体不好
and that you've been
不大方便
undergoing treatment lately.
最近又在治疗
Don't worry.
你看
The treatment was pretty good.
治疗的效果还挺好的
Yes.
是啊
You're looking very well.
你的精气神看着很不错
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Well,
这个
I'm so flattered that you come
你们这样还跑一趟
all the way here.
我真是不好意思
It's okay.
应该的 应该的
If it wasn't
都怪我这病
my illness,
这身体太不争气了
I should have seen you
那孩子们都结婚了
before the kids got married.
咱们也一直没见上
It's alright.
现在见也不晚
Mr. and Mrs. Tu,
亲家
Yuheng has been
我们家昱恒呢
an introvert
他打小啊
since he was a kid.
性格比较内向
He's not good at words
不会说话
and kind of oblivious.
也不懂事
If he does something
要是 有什么
that may upset you,
给你们添麻烦
I apologize for him.
惹你们生气了
Please forgive him.
一定多担待啊
It's okay.
没有
Yuheng is a very
小纪这孩子呀
good boy.
特别懂事
Yeah.
对 对 对
We can tell
一看呢就是
he's well-educated.
受过好的教育啊
Must be well-taught by his family.
一看就家教好
He's a gentleman.
有礼貌
Yes.
对 对 对
That's a relief.
那我就放心了
But,
但是
I'm still worried
但是我还是有点担心
that they may not
这 小两口
get used to
刚结婚
their marriage life.
我怕磨合不好
I heard it
刚才
when Xiaoning
我好像
blurted out that
听筱柠说漏嘴
they don't
他们
sleep in the same room.
还在分房睡呢
Try this one.
你尝尝这个菜
So fresh.
好嫩啊
This vegetable
这个季节
at this time
这个菜
is the freshest.
鲜嫩啊
Alright.
行了
Help yourself.
你自己来吧
Why did you come back alone?
你今儿一个人回来的
What about Yuheng?
小纪呢
He's busy.
他忙
He's a leader.
人家当领导的
Of course he's busy.
都挺忙的
You don't have to serve him.
你不用管你爸了
Leave some for yourself.
你自己喝点啊
Have some soup.
喝点汤
It's good for you.
润一润
Well,
那个
I've just changed your
你那屋啊
bedspread and comforter
刚好那床单被罩
in your room.
我都给你换好了
Why don't you stay over tonight?
今天晚上要不在家住吧
Stay over?
在家住
What about...
那小
The room is good enough...
小屋挺好的呀
Right?
是不是
I've cleaned it up already.
小屋收拾了
Yeah, I see.
我就说那小屋
The bedroom
那小屋
is lovely after your mom's
让你妈这一收拾
cleaning,
还挺好的
innit?
是吧 你
You haven't stayed here
从你结婚了以后
since you got married.
就没在这儿住过
The room's getting lonely.
那小屋都冷清了
Stay over for a night.
住一晚上吧
You can keep your mom company.
好好陪陪你妈
Mom, if you don't want me to go,
妈你要是想我的话
I'll stay home a few more days.
我就在家多住几天
Okay!
好呀
Sweet and spicy shredded pork.
这鱼香肉丝
You have to try this one.
你必须得尝尝
I tell you.
我跟你讲
Your dad cooked it.
这是你爸做的
He just learned.
他刚学会的
He said it should be good.
说特别好吃
He made this the first time.
今第一次做
You have to try it.
你必须得尝尝啊
She's asleep?
姑娘午睡了
I thought you'd planned to
我以为你把他们俩
get them here
弄来啊
to appease them
是想撺掇着
and stop their argument.
他们和好呢
That's what I've planned.
我倒是这么想的呀
But now,
那谁想到
Xiaoning came back alone
筱柠自己回来了
without Yuheng.
没带小纪
That means,
那就说明
she's unwilling to stay with him.
她跟小纪待着不舒服
Give her some room and time.
让她一个人静静吧
It's not the argument
这两口子呀
but the silence
不怕吵
that harms the marriage.
就怕冷啊
Don't worry.
怕什么呀
Yuheng is a man.
小纪一个大男人
If he didn't try to solve it first,
不主动解决问题
why would our daughter be expected
难道还让我们家女儿
to solve it?
上赶着
If they don't talk, they may separate.
这冷着冷着就容易散的
What if they get divorced
你说万一他俩一冲动
on impulse?
要是闹离婚怎么办呢
What are you thinking?
不是这才哪儿到哪儿啊
"Get divorced"?
就离婚了
Don't jinx it!
这个乌鸦嘴
Help me with it.
给我叠上
Young people today
现在的年轻人
don't value marriage
都不太把这个
as much as people did in the past.
结婚离婚当回事
After the property is divided,
财产一分
and they
是吧
are all single again.
又都恢复单身了
How about
要不
have some when it's not cold yet.
趁热先吃点吧
Meeting with you
和你见面
is already traitorous enough.
已经是叛徒行为
If I eat your food,
要是再吃你的东西
I'll be guilty of accepting a bribe.
就是收受贿赂罪加一等
Don't get me wrong.
可千万别误会啊
I'm not trying to bribe you.
我不是为了贿赂你
I...
我
You know me and Xiaoning.
你也知道我跟筱柠
I
我呀
just have something to ask you.
就是想请教请教你
What's she
她最近
been thinking lately?
到底在想什么
You're in a relationship.
你们俩现在是男女朋友
You're the one that should be close to her.
最亲密的关系之一
If you wanna know,
她想什么你应该自己
just ask her yourself.
去问她呀
But,
不是
if she's always
如果她要一直
this emotional,
都带着情绪的话
I can't know her true feelings
我就没办法判断
under the emotions.
她真实地感受
Now we're talking.
态度还算可以
What's your question?
说吧
You know
你也知道
she's been
她最近
arguing with me
一直在跟我闹别扭
because of what I did
是因为我们行里
to Zhao Fanggang at work.
赵方刚的事情
And?
然后呢
I wanna know
然后我就想知道
why she cared
她为什么会因为
so much
赵方刚的事情
about him.
那么在意
Did you really think
你不会觉得
it's that Zhao
她在意的
she's been
真的是那个什么
caring about?
赵方刚吧
If not, then what?
那不然因为什么
You didn't even know
你连筱柠为什么生气
why she's mad at you.
都不知道
You deserve it if she dumped you.
被踹了真是活该
She may be angry.
你说她生气也好
She may be disappointed.
失望也罢
How could it be just
怎么可能单纯
because of a coworker?
是因为那个同事呢
It must be because of
那肯定就是因为
your personality
你的性格
and the way you handle things.
跟你处理问题的方式呀
Still don't get it?
还不懂
All in all,
总的来说就是
you're making her feel very insecure.
你让她非常没有安全感
Feeling insecure?
没有安全感
Yeah!
对呀
Think about it.
你想啊
You're her leader,
你们俩是上下级
and more than
但也并不是
that.
单纯的上下级
What you do
你的一举一动
can impact greatly
对她来说影响力
on her.
可是非常地大的
You
你
tried to establish authority.
去那办公室立威
For any misunderstanding,
同事他们误会了
you didn't explain at all.
你也不帮忙解释半句
And you deal with
还用自己
Zhao Fanggang
执拗的方式去处理
in your own hard way.
那个什么赵方刚的问题
All of these combined.
这些种种加在一起
Then,
你想想
what would she think?
你让她怎么想啊
If I were her,
反正要是我
I'd think you're a
我肯定觉得你就是一个
stubborn, arrogant,
固执 自大
and inconsiderate person,
不考虑别人感受的人
and hate that I chose a wrong man.
恨自己当时识人不清
I even wanna immediately dump you.
一脚把你踹了
C'mon, I...
不是 我
And the most important thing.
还有特别重要的
You don't talk.
你不长嘴
It is the most
不长嘴啊
deadly factor to any relationships.
可是亲密关系里的大忌
You get F minus
你真是每条
on every move.
都撞枪口上
Isn't it a bribe to you?
不说这是贿赂吗
It doesn't count.
什么都不说才是贿赂呢
I'm helping Xiaoning
我是在帮筱柠
with her relationship.
解决情感问题
It's my reward.
这是我应得的
Oh, yummy.
还挺好吃
Look at him.
你看他 你看他
Your dad was so young
你看你爸那会儿
at that time.
多年轻啊
We actually got married
我跟你爸呀就是闪婚
within a week
认识不到一个星期
after we met.
就结婚了
It's our first time to be
大家都是第一次
a wife
给别人当老婆
or a husband.
第一次给别人当丈夫
It's normal to feel uncomfortable.
所以就不适应
It's like
你就想着好像
someone just
突然有一个人
came into your life
就进到你生活里了
and
然后
disrupted
打破了你
your life.
所有的生活习惯
I remembered
你别说了
I'd like to be up early
那个时候吧
when I was young.
我喜欢早起
But you dad loved to stay up late.
你爸喜欢晚睡
We were not used to
我们俩的生物钟
each other's routines.
就根本没有碰到一块去
For the first three months,
头三个月
we didn't even have breakfast together.
早饭都没在一块吃过
But I remember when I was in school,
那我记得我上学那会儿
my dad used to get up in the morning
都是我爸早上起来
and make me breakfast.
给我做早饭呀
We've been together for a long time.
那都磨合多长时间了
I made him to get up early by arguing.
我跟他吵出来的
I can't imagine him
但我爸应该
daring to argue with you.
不敢跟您吵架啊妈
For as long as
打我记事起
I can remember,
我就觉得我爸
I think he has always been
一直在诠释四个字
subservient to you.
唯命是从
Every couple could fight.
哪有夫妻不吵架的
It's perfectly normal
你说小两口有个矛盾
for couples to have conflicts
有个意见不合
or disagreements.
那不是正常吗
The key is,
关键呀
they should try hard
要看大家
to solve the problems.
用不用心去解决
What?
怎么了
You still don't wanna
还不跟我说
talk about you and Yuheng?
你跟小纪的事啊
I heard
我可是听
from Yuheng's mom that
小纪妈妈说了啊
you two haven't been
你们俩
sleeping in the same room.
一直没住在一起
Marriage is a great change in your life.
这生活步子大了
It's okay that you
不适应
haven't gotten used to it.
其实正常的
You can
那些生活的步骤
improve it
可以
one step at a time.
一步一步地去推进
But you have to figure out
但是你必须得想清楚
what the problem
你们之间的问题
is between you two.
到底出在哪里
I just think we're moving
我就是觉得我们两个
too fast into a new
步入一段新关系期
stage of life.
太快了
I'm afraid I'm not thinking clearly.
我怕我自己没想清楚
Life consists of
生活
trivial things and numerous
反正就是柴米油盐
thoughts and feelings.
千头万绪
There are things
有些事情啊
you may never figure out.
可能永远都想不清楚
I think that
我是觉得
if you have decided
如果你们两个
to spend your lives together,
决定在一起过日子了
then you should try to
那就铆着劲
make life as good as possible.
好好过日子
If one day you feel
如果有一天觉得
you can't go on,
实在是过不下去了
then just break up.
那就掰了算了
"Break up"?
掰了算了
What's wrong with that?
那有什么不行的呀
If you meet someone you love,
遇见爱的
then love again.
那就再爱呗
If you don't,
遇不见
You can move back in
你就搬回来
with us,
就像现在这样
just like now.
跟爸爸妈妈一块住啊
But
不过呢
I just don't think
我就是觉得吧
my daughter
我女儿啊
can give up
不是那么容易放弃
or back down that easily.
那么就容易退缩的人
Mom.
妈
You're saying this
你说这些
to encourage me
还是希望
to keep going, right?
我再继续前行对吧
You have
你呢
the courage to go forward
有勇往直前的勇气
and safety net to retreat.
也有急流勇退的底气
Your father and I
我跟你爸
are your safety net.
就是你的底气
But if you wanna retreat,
不过你退了之后啊
don't forget to
记得把那个生活费
pay your living expenses.
按月交一下
You'll charge me for living here?
我还要交生活费
You didn't charge me before!
那我以前都不用交
I'd like you to make it up to me.
那你把以前那些补上啊
No!
不
Sweet and sour pork?
糖醋肉
I can do this.
加油